Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Assistance et administration : regardez sur kissasia.cam ou kisskh.org
[Whispers of Fate]
[Whispers of Fate]
[Episode 38]
[Episode 38]
Why is Master only just getting back?
Why is Master only just getting back?
Why has he been acting so secretive lately?
Why has he been acting so secretive lately?
Chunji?
Chunji?
Master.
Master.
You're still up at this hour?
You're still up at this hour?
Where are your royal guards?
Where are your royal guards?
It's actually quite uncomfortable
It's actually quite uncomfortable
being followed by them every day.
being followed by them every day.
Besides,
En plus,
I grew up here.
I grew up here.
This is my home.
This is my home.
Who would want
Who would want
to be followed around even at home?
to be followed around even at home?
I remember when you
I remember when you
first came here—
first came here—
you sat right here
you sat right here
watching me practice calligraphy.
watching me practice calligraphy.
You were so mischievous,
You were so mischievous,
sneakily drawing on my face
sneakily drawing on my face
while I was sleeping.
while I was sleeping.
In the blink of an eye,
In the blink of an eye,
you've grown so much.
you've grown so much.
Yes, indeed.
Yes, indeed.
Later, you taught me swordsmanship.
Later, you taught me swordsmanship.
Because this place is remote,
Because this place is remote,
I could continue practicing here at night
I could continue practicing here at night
whatever swordsmanship I couldn't master during the day.
whatever swordsmanship I couldn't master during the day.
It seems like it's been so long
It seems like it's been so long
since I've had a heart-to-heart talk
since I've had a heart-to-heart talk
with you like this, Master.
with you like this, Master.
Chunji,
Chunji,
do you resent me?
do you resent me?
I wouldn't dare.
I wouldn't dare.
Wouldn't dare?
Wouldn't dare?
Then you do resent me.
Then you do resent me.
It's my fault
It's my fault
for raising you to be too demanding of yourself.
for raising you to be too demanding of yourself.
You've always worked hard,
You've always worked hard,
always seeking approval.
always seeking approval.
I...
JE...
have indeed failed you in some ways.
have indeed failed you in some ways.
No.
Non.
I am the one who has failed you, Master.
I am the one who has failed you, Master.
Master...
Master...
If one day
If one day
you discover...
you discover...
Just say what you want to say.
Just say what you want to say.
If you discover I've done
If you discover I've done
many wrong things behind your back
many wrong things behind your back
and told many lies...
and told many lies...
Actually, I didn't cook
Actually, I didn't cook
the medicinal porridge that day.
the medicinal porridge that day.
You think I didn't notice?
You think I didn't notice?
You couldn't even roast a sweet potato when you were little.
You couldn't even roast a sweet potato when you were little.
That porridge was
That porridge was
fresh, fragrant, sweet, and rich in ingredients.
fresh, fragrant, sweet, and rich in ingredients.
It was clearly made
It was clearly made
by a palace cook.
by a palace cook.
Nothing escapes your notice, Master.
Nothing escapes your notice, Master.
Of course.
Bien sûr.
It's late.
It's late.
I'll walk you back to your room.
I'll walk you back to your room.
Zhong Chunji,
Zhong Chunji,
why have you become so cowardly?
why have you become so cowardly?
Tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
I'll definitely confess everything to Master tomorrow.
I'll definitely confess everything to Master tomorrow.
Come on.
Allez.
Time to go back to sleep.
Time to go back to sleep.
Coming.
Coming.
Master.
Master.
It feels like I'm back in my childhood.
It feels like I'm back in my childhood.
Orders from Sword Master Tang:
Orders from Sword Master Tang:
While Mr. Chi is detained,
While Mr. Chi is detained,
no one is allowed to approach him.
no one is allowed to approach him.
I've brought some food and wine
I've brought some food and wine
and just want to see him briefly.
and just want to see him briefly.
Food is allowed,
Food is allowed,
but after our inspection,
but after our inspection,
we'll deliver it for you, miss.
we'll deliver it for you, miss.
We have our duties to fulfill.
We have our duties to fulfill.
Please understand.
Please understand.
Of course, I understand.
Of course, I understand.
I'm the one intruding.
I'm the one intruding.
Well then...
Well then...
I'll trouble you with this.
I'll trouble you with this.
With this final vial of serum,
With this final vial of serum,
Chi Yun should be able to hold on
Chi Yun should be able to hold on
until the antidote is made.
until the antidote is made.
Mr. Tang!
Mr. Tang!
Mr. Tang, bad news.
Mr. Tang, bad news.
Chi's poison has flared up.
Chi's poison has flared up.
He injured the guards and broke out of the cell.
He injured the guards and broke out of the cell.
Chi Yun was fine yesterday.
Chi Yun was fine yesterday.
How could his poison suddenly flare up?
How could his poison suddenly flare up?
The guards said
The guards said
Xifang Tao came yesterday.
Xifang Tao came yesterday.
But they didn't let her in.
But they didn't let her in.
Enemy attack on the fortress.
Enemy attack on the fortress.
Disaster imminent.
Disaster imminent.
Extremely urgent.
Extremely urgent.
Return immediately.
Return immediately.
He escaped?
He escaped?
How could you let him escape?
How could you let him escape?
If his poison has erupted,
If his poison has erupted,
the villagers at the foot of the mountain
les villageois au pied de la montagne
will be in danger.
sera en danger.
How could you all be so careless?
Comment avez-vous pu être aussi insouciants ?
Xifang Tao!
Xifang Tao !
Miss Xifang.
Mlle Xifang.
[Central Plains Sword Alliance]
[Alliance des Épées des Plaines Centrales]
-Hello, Sword Master Tang.
-Bonjour, Maître d'armes Tang.
Let's go.
Allons-y.
Mr. Tang!
Monsieur Tang !
I already know about the situation.
Je suis déjà au courant de la situation.
There's something suspicious about Chi Yun's sudden madness.
La folie soudaine de Chi Yun a quelque chose de suspect .
It may be dangerous for you to search for him alone.
Il peut être dangereux pour vous de le rechercher seul.
Shui Duopo came to me last night
Shui Duopo m'est apparu hier soir
and said the prescription this time
et a dit l'ordonnance cette fois-ci
is absolutely foolproof.
est absolument infaillible.
Once this matter is settled,
Une fois cette affaire réglée,
my worries
mes soucis
will mostly be gone.
La plupart auront disparu.
As for finding Mr. Chi,
Quant à retrouver M. Chi,
let the Sword Alliance help you.
Laissez l'Alliance des Épées vous aider.
Master Shao.
Maître Shao.
I'll handle
Je m'en occuperai.
Chi Yun's matter myself.
Le problème de Chi Yun, c'est moi.
Wait!
Attendez!
You...
Toi...
Don't push yourself too hard.
Ne vous surmenez pas.
Don't try to shoulder
N'essayez pas de porter sur l'épaule
everything alone.
tout seul.
And don't treat the help of others
Et ne méprisez pas l'aide des autres.
as a burden!
comme un fardeau !
Mr. Tang,
Monsieur Tang,
you're still young.
Tu es encore jeune.
You have a long road
Le chemin est encore long.
ahead of you.
devant vous.
Everyone, sooner or later,
Tout le monde, tôt ou tard,
grows weary and lonely.
se lasse et se sent seul.
The jianghu is in turmoil.
Le jianghu est en proie à l'agitation.
Having someone by your side
Avoir quelqu'un à ses côtés
is always better than walking alone!
C'est toujours mieux que de marcher seul !
Master Shao,
Maître Shao,
Xifang Tao still has allies in the Sword Alliance.
Xifang Tao compte encore des alliés au sein de l'Alliance de l'Épée.
You need to stay
Vous devez rester
to prevent internal conflict.
pour prévenir les conflits internes.
But you...
Mais vous...
Mr. Tang.
Monsieur Tang.
I once thought you could be
J'ai un jour pensé que tu pouvais être
the one to shake up the jianghu
celui qui va bouleverser le jianghu
and reshape its order.
et en modifier l'ordre.
But circumstances shift without warning,
Mais les circonstances changent sans prévenir,
and and we who are caught in the game can only submit to fate.
Et nous qui sommes pris au piège de ce jeu, nous ne pouvons que nous soumettre au destin.
I hope that one day
J'espère qu'un jour
you'll stop forcing yourself
tu arrêteras de te forcer
and learn to take care of yourself.
et apprenez à prendre soin de vous.
Stone,
Pierre,
Master Tang's friend is in trouble.
L'ami de Maître Tang est en difficulté.
Instead of going to comfort him,
Au lieu d'aller le réconforter,
what are you doing here?
que faites-vous ici?
Planting a tree.
Planter un arbre.
Planting a tree?
Planter un arbre ?
Why plant a tree now?
Pourquoi planter un arbre maintenant ?
Just...
Juste...
suddenly...
soudainement...
need to...
besoin de...
plant a tree.
Plantez un arbre.
Let's go. Let's go.
Allons-y. Allons-y.
Why is Stone acting so strangely today?
Pourquoi Stone se comporte-t-il si étrangement aujourd'hui ?
Usually he clings to Mr. Tang,
D'habitude, il s'accroche à M. Tang.
but now that something this serious has happened,
mais maintenant qu'un événement aussi grave s'est produit,
how can he still be so calm
Comment peut-il rester aussi calme ?
planting a tree here?
planter un arbre ici ?
Master!
Maître!
Master seems distracted
Le maître semble distrait.
and is carrying medicine.
et transporte des médicaments.
Is he going to deliver it to someone?
Va-t-il le livrer à quelqu'un ?
Chi Yun's incident definitely wasn't an accident.
L'incident impliquant Chi Yun n'était certainement pas un accident.
I must deliver this prescription quickly,
Je dois livrer cette ordonnance rapidement,
before anything else goes wrong.
avant que quoi que ce soit d'autre ne tourne mal.
Master Shao, you're in such a hurry.
Maître Shao, vous êtes bien pressé.
Where are you heading?
Où allez-vous ?
Who are you?
Qui es-tu?
Master...
Maître...
Master!
Maître!
Who are you?
Qui es-tu?
Why did you hurt my master?
Pourquoi avez-vous fait du mal à mon maître ?
Chunji.
Chunji.
Leave me behind and run.
Laissez-moi derrière vous et fuyez.
How could I leave you behind?
Comment pourrais-je te laisser derrière moi ?
Only a tool
Un simple outil
can be a true tool.
peut être un véritable outil.
Nice to meet you.
Ravi de vous rencontrer.
You can call me
Vous pouvez m'appeler
Ghostly Peony.
Pivoine fantomatique.
Ghostly Peony, you're still alive?
Pivoine fantomatique, tu es toujours en vie ?
Chunji,
Chunji,
fire the signal flare now!
Tirez la fusée de signalisation maintenant !
Have you thought it through, Princess?
Y avez-vous bien réfléchi, Princesse ?
Xifang Tao,
Xifang Tao
what exactly are you
Qu'êtes-vous exactement ?
and Ghostly Peony trying to do?
et la pivoine fantomatique qui essaie de faire ?
Godfather, looks like
Le Parrain, on dirait
you've fully recovered.
Vous êtes complètement rétabli.
Liu Yan betrayed us.
Liu Yan nous a trahis.
The poisoned people have been
Les personnes empoisonnées ont été
transferred to Sword King City by Tang Lici.
transféré à la Cité du Roi Épée par Tang Lici.
This amount of Black Tuli
Cette quantité de tuli noir
is far from enough.
c'est loin d'être suffisant.
Godfather, you haven't given up
Parrain, vous n'avez pas abandonné.
on our master's mission.
sur la mission de notre maître.
I heard
J'ai entendu
the bronze tree has been destroyed,
L'arbre de bronze a été détruit.
and our master's plan failed.
et le plan de notre maître a échoué.
Don't you want freedom, Godfather?
Tu ne veux pas la liberté, Parrain ?
Freedom?
Liberté?
The freedom to decide
La liberté de décider
your own destiny.
votre propre destin.
Why do I need freedom?
Pourquoi ai-je besoin de liberté ?
A bottle exists
Il existe une bouteille
to hold water.
contenir de l'eau.
A free bottle
Une bouteille gratuite
is nothing but useless trash.
Ce ne sont que des déchets inutiles.
Strings are meant
Les cordes sont destinées
to be tied to the tuning pegs of instruments.
être attachés aux chevilles d'accord des instruments.
Free strings
cordes libres
are just useless threads.
Ce ne sont que des fils de discussion inutiles.
But people aren't tools.
Mais les gens ne sont pas des outils.
Perhaps a bottle wants to hold wine.
Peut-être qu'une bouteille a envie de contenir du vin.
Perhaps strings
Peut-être des cordes
want to be fishing lines.
Je veux être des lignes de pêche.
That's merely changing
Il s'agit simplement de changer
from one kind of tool to another.
d'un type d'outil à un autre.
People who find their purpose
Les personnes qui trouvent leur raison d'être
are useful tools.
sont des outils utiles.
Those who can't find their purpose
Ceux qui ne trouvent pas leur raison d'être
are no different
ne sont pas différents
from trash.
des ordures.
Only after dying once did I understand.
Ce n'est qu'après être mort une fois que j'ai compris.
As long as our master lives,
Tant que notre maître vivra,
a puppet remains a puppet.
Une marionnette reste une marionnette.
Even with thoughts and feelings...
Même avec des pensées et des sentiments...
how is that different
En quoi est-ce différent ?
from being a tool?
d'être un outil ?
Rather than discussing illusory freedom,
Plutôt que de discuter de la liberté illusoire,
Godfather, why don't you just tell me
Parrain, pourquoi ne me le dis-tu pas tout simplement ?
what you want me to do?
Que voulez-vous que je fasse ?
I need more Black Tuli.
J'ai besoin de plus de Black Tuli.
Tang Lici...
Tang Li...
keeps ruining my plans.
Il ne cesse de ruiner mes plans.
Godfather, your trap in West Wind Garden
Parrain, ton piège à West Wind Garden
wasn't completely useless.
n'était pas complètement inutile.
Chi Yun's poisoning
L'empoisonnement de Chi Yun
has already consumed most of
a déjà consommé la majeure partie de
Tang Lici's energy.
L'énergie de Tang Lici.
So, he'll definitely
Donc, il le fera certainement
have someone else
avoir quelqu'un d'autre
contact Liu Yan.
contacter Liu Yan.
Whoever that person is,
Quelle que soit cette personne,
following them gives us
Les suivre nous donne
a much better chance of finding Liu Yan
une bien meilleure chance de trouver Liu Yan
than following Tang Lici.
que de suivre Tang Lici.
Godfather.
Parrain.
I've already searched
J'ai déjà cherché
for clues in the direction
pour des indices dans la direction
Master Shao was heading.
Maître Shao se dirigeait vers lui.
There's a small mountain village ahead.
Un petit village de montagne se trouve plus loin.
Liu Yan is indeed there.
Liu Yan est bien là.
Still one step too late.
Encore un pas trop tard.
No.
Non.
I must let Mr. Tang know
Je dois en informer M. Tang
that Ghostly Peony is
que la pivoine fantomatique est
behind Xifang Tao.
derrière Xifang Tao.
Between Chunji and me,
Entre Chunji et moi,
one of us must make it out alive.
L'un de nous doit s'en sortir vivant.
Princess.
Princesse.
Have you decided
Avez-vous décidé
which side you want to stand on?
De quel côté voulez-vous vous ranger ?
Princess, you're a clever person.
Princesse, vous êtes une personne intelligente.
Coming here from the Sword Alliance
Je viens de l'Alliance de l'Épée.
will take at least an hour.
Cela prendra au moins une heure.
An hour
Une heure
is more than enough time
c'est largement suffisant comme temps
for us to kill Master Shao
pour que nous tuions Maître Shao
and spare your life.
et épargnez votre vie.
When that happens,
Lorsque cela se produit,
we'll simply tell everyone
Nous allons simplement le dire à tout le monde.
that Master Shao
ce Maître Shao
discovered you were an impostor,
J'ai découvert que tu étais un imposteur,
that you killed your master
que tu as tué ton maître
to preserve your wealth and status,
pour préserver votre richesse et votre statut,
and that I,
et que moi,
Xifang Tao, arrived too late
Xifang Tao est arrivé trop tard.
to save him.
pour le sauver.
You think people will believe you
Tu penses que les gens vont te croire.
just because you say so?
Simplement parce que vous le dites ?
What I just said
Ce que je viens de dire
is indeed false.
c'est effectivement faux.
But the fake tattoo on your body
Mais le faux tatouage sur ton corps
is enough to turn my lies
Cela suffit à transformer mes mensonges
into truth.
dans la vérité.
After all, wouldn't the words
Après tout, les mots ne seraient-ils pas
of an innocent person like me
d'une personne innocente comme moi
be more credible than those of
être plus crédibles que ceux de
someone who's definitely a fake princess?
Une vraie fausse princesse ?
Chunji,
Chunji,
is what she's saying true?
Ce qu'elle dit est-il vrai ?
Princess,
Princesse,
are you willing to take that gamble?
Êtes-vous prêt à prendre ce risque ?
Tai'e Sword's
L'épée Tai'e
Offering!
Offre!
Heaven-Changing Scripture—
Les Écritures qui changent le ciel —
Reverse Yin and Yang.
Yin et Yang inversés.
Chunji,
Chunji,
I once said
J'ai dit un jour
that we should be good people
que nous devrions être de bonnes personnes
even if it comes at a price.
même si cela a un prix.
Remember,
Souviens-toi,
I never blamed you.
Je ne t'en ai jamais voulu.
Chunji, run!
Chunji, cours !
You must survive
Vous devez survivre
and tell everyone
et dites-le à tout le monde
that Ghostly Peony is still alive!
Cette pivoine fantomatique est toujours vivante !
Heaven-Changing Scripture—
Les Écritures qui changent le ciel —
Remaking Heaven and Earth.
Recréer le Ciel et la Terre.
Master!
Maître!
Injured by the Heaven-Changing Scripture—
Blessé par les Écritures qui changent le ciel —
people will only believe you're
Les gens croiront seulement que vous êtes
killed by the Rebirth Scroll.
Tué par le Parchemin de la Renaissance.
Master!
Maître!
Princess,
Princesse,
your master
votre maître
is down to his last breath.
Il est à l'article de la mort.
Are you sure you want to waste
Êtes-vous sûr de vouloir gaspiller
your time on me?
Tu me consacres du temps ?
Master.
Maître.
Master...
Maître...
You must hold on.
Vous devez tenir bon.
I'll go back
Je retournerai
and find the best
et trouver le meilleur
imperial doctors in the world to treat you!
Les meilleurs médecins impériaux du monde pour vous soigner !
So this is the bond between master and disciple.
Voilà donc le lien entre maître et disciple.
Well then...
Eh bien…
You must hold on.
Vous devez tenir bon.
Master.
Maître.
Godfather.
Parrain.
Leave it to me.
Laissez-moi faire.
Master!
Maître!
Ms. Zhong,
Mme Zhong,
I'll give you a chance.
Je te donnerai une chance.
♪ The wind blows at night ♪
♪ Le vent souffle la nuit ♪
♪Stars fall into the woods ♪
♪Les étoiles tombent dans les bois♪
♪ When will I wake up from this dream? ♪
♪ Quand vais-je me réveiller de ce rêve ? ♪
Take this sword...
Prenez cette épée...
♪ Ahead of me is a dead end ♪
♪ Devant moi se trouve une impasse ♪
♪ I feel sorrow for our parting ♪
♪ Je suis triste de notre séparation ♪
and kill him.
et le tuer.
♪ I wish I had followed the back of you ♪
♪ J'aurais aimé te suivre ♪
Then I'll let you live.
Alors je te laisserai vivre.
♪ I only hope we can live and die together ♪
♪ J'espère seulement que nous pourrons vivre et mourir ensemble ♪
Girl.
Fille.
It's better for one to survive
Il vaut mieux survivre à l'un d'entre eux
♪ Even if our fate plans differently ♪
♪ Même si le destin en a décidé autrement ♪
than for both to die.
plutôt que de mourir tous les deux.
♪ I'm guarding ♪
♪ Je garde ♪
Only the living have a chance to turn things around.
Seuls les vivants ont une chance de changer la donne.
♪ The memories fallen out of the circle of time ♪
♪ Les souvenirs tombés hors du cercle du temps ♪
♪ All plants have burned into ashes ♪
♪ Toutes les plantes ont été réduites en cendres ♪
♪ Clouds are sighing ♪
♪ Les nuages ​​soupirent ♪
♪ The ten-century-old gaze leaves no trails ♪
♪ Le regard vieux de dix siècles ne laisse aucune trace ♪
♪ Mortals barely have access to all truths ♪
♪ Les mortels ont à peine accès à toutes les vérités ♪
♪ They're puzzled by mysteries ♪
♪ Ils sont intrigués par les mystères ♪
♪ Among all the ebbs and flows, what day is today? ♪
♪ Au milieu de tous ces flux et reflux, quel jour sommes-nous ? ♪
♪ I long to go through the journey of life with you ♪
♪ J'aspire à parcourir le chemin de la vie avec toi ♪
♪ Even if we won't meet again afterwards ♪
♪ Même si nous ne nous revoyons plus après ♪
You will never understand...
Vous ne comprendrez jamais...
♪ It's an experience where we're destined ♪
♪ C'est une expérience à laquelle nous sommes prédestinés ♪
the bond between master and disciple.
le lien entre maître et disciple.
♪ To stay within boundaries and constraints ♪
♪ Rester dans les limites et les contraintes ♪
♪ Spend every day and night with you ♪
♪ Passer chaque jour et chaque nuit avec toi ♪
♪ And to be with you for every year ♪
♪ Et être avec toi chaque année ♪
♪ Side by side ♪
♪ Côte à côte ♪
♪ We'll watch flowers fall ♪
♪ Nous regarderons les fleurs tomber ♪
♪ And propose toasts with empty glasses ♪
♪ Et portez des toasts avec des verres vides ♪
♪ Side by side ♪
♪ Côte à côte ♪
Chunji...
Chunji...
♪ When people have been through all sufferings ♪
♪ Quand les gens auront enduré toutes les souffrances ♪
Master.
Maître.
I'm sorry.
Je suis désolé.
♪ And drained of tears ♪
♪ Et les larmes taries ♪
I didn't teach you well.
Je ne t'ai pas bien enseigné.
♪ We'll hold our shared aspiration as a pact ♪
♪ Nous garderons notre aspiration commune comme un pacte ♪
Being my disciple...
Être mon disciple...
♪ To make our journey worthwhile ♪
♪ Pour que notre voyage en vaille la peine ♪
must have been hard, right?
Ça a dû être difficile, n'est-ce pas ?
♪ Joy, anger, grief, disgust and desires ♪
♪ Joie, colère, chagrin, dégoût et désirs ♪
No...
Non...
♪ Emotions could impede you ♪
♪ Les émotions pourraient vous freiner ♪
Master...
Maître...
♪ The enchanting whisper of spring sounds like you ♪
♪ Le murmure enchanteur du printemps ressemble à toi ♪
You're the best master I could ever have.
Tu es le meilleur maître que j'aurais pu avoir.
♪ The moon shines again ♪
♪ La lune brille à nouveau ♪
♪ But not on the deceased's clothes ♪
♪ Mais pas sur les vêtements du défunt ♪
♪ I'll be like an oar from now on ♪
♪ Je serai comme une rame désormais ♪
♪ I'll remember the past ♪
♪ Je me souviendrai du passé ♪
♪ Where will we reunite? ♪
♪ Où nous retrouverons-nous ? ♪
♪ It's an experience where we're destined ♪
♪ C'est une expérience à laquelle nous sommes prédestinés ♪
Master!
Maître!
♪ To stay within boundaries and constraints ♪
♪ Rester dans les limites et les contraintes ♪
Master!
Maître!
♪ Spend every day and night with you ♪
♪ Passer chaque jour et chaque nuit avec toi ♪
♪ And to be with you for every year ♪
♪ Et être avec toi chaque année ♪
Master!
Maître!
♪ Side by side ♪
♪ Côte à côte ♪
♪ We'll watch flowers fall ♪
♪ Nous regarderons les fleurs tomber ♪
♪ And propose toasts with empty glasses ♪
♪ Et portez des toasts avec des verres vides ♪
Without you,
Sans toi,
I truly have nothing left...
Je n'ai vraiment plus rien...
♪ Side by side ♪
♪ Côte à côte ♪
♪ When people have been through all sufferings ♪
♪ Quand les gens auront enduré toutes les souffrances ♪
This is the deafening crash
C'est le fracas assourdissant
that comes the instant
qui arrive l'instant
♪ And drained of tears ♪
♪ Et les larmes taries ♪
one hits the ground and shatters.
L'une d'elles touche le sol et se brise.
♪ I will no longer wish for eternity ♪
♪ Je ne souhaiterai plus l'éternité ♪
Why?
Pourquoi?
♪ I will only hope to ♪
♪ J'espère seulement ♪
Where am I?
Où suis-je ?
Huoyun Fortress.
Forteresse de Huoyun.
I need to go to Huoyun Fortress to save them.
Je dois aller à la forteresse de Huoyun pour les sauver.
Which fool
Quel imbécile !
dares to mess with my Huoyun Fortress?
Qui oserait s'en prendre à ma forteresse de Huoyun ?
I heard there's a poison outbreak outside.
J'ai entendu dire qu'il y a une épidémie d'empoisonnement dehors.
It's spreading rapidly.
Cela se propage rapidement.
They say those poisoned people
Ils disent que ces personnes empoisonnées
have horrifying faces and are contagious.
Ils ont des visages terrifiants et sont contagieux.
We need to stay away from them.
Nous devons rester loin d'eux.
Indeed.
En effet.
Excuse me.
Excusez-moi.
Where is Huoyun Fortress?
Où se trouve la forteresse de Huoyun ?
A poisoned person!
Une personne empoisonnée !
-A poisoned person!
-Une personne empoisonnée !
Run!
Courir!
Hurry! Run!
Vite ! Courez !
Let's go get help!
Allons chercher de l'aide !
Darn it.
Zut !
Is he somewhere nearby?
Est-il dans les environs ?
Where?
Où?
Where did he go?
Où est-il allé ?
Exactly.
Exactement.
There.
Là.
Look at that.
Regardez ça.
That one ahead!
Celui-ci, devant !
Hey, man!
Hé, mec !
You're looking for Huoyun Fortress, right?
Vous cherchez la forteresse de Huoyun, n'est-ce pas ?
We're from Huoyun Fortress.
Nous venons de la forteresse de Huoyun.
Are you blind?
Êtes-vous aveugle ?
Boss?
Chef?
Chi?
Dépenser?
How could you not recognize me?
Comment as-tu pu ne pas me reconnaître ?
Boss, it really is you!
Patron, c'est bien vous !
What happened to your face?
Qu'est-il arrivé à ton visage ?
It's nothing.
Ce n'est rien.
I got a bit poisoned.
J'ai été un peu empoisonné.
Poisoned?
Empoisonné?
Where's the bastard
Où est ce salaud ?
who poisoned you?
Qui vous a empoisonné ?
Guys,
Les gars,
let's avenge our boss!
Vengons notre patron !
-Yes, avenge our boss!
-Oui, vengeons notre patron !
Alright, alright.
D'accord, d'accord.
That one is already dead.
Celui-là est déjà mort.
Why are you all here?
Pourquoi êtes-vous tous ici ?
The letter.
La lettre.
We came to rescue you.
Nous sommes venus vous secourir.
Look.
Regarder.
We received a distress letter.
Nous avons reçu une lettre de détresse.
I never wrote this.
Je n'ai jamais écrit ça.
Who sent it to you?
Qui vous l'a envoyé ?
It's forged?
C'est un faux ?
Forged?
Forgé?
The rogue went through all this trouble to forge a letter.
Le malfaiteur s'est donné tout ce mal pour falsifier une lettre.
What for?
Pourquoi?
Who cares?
Qui s'en soucie?
As long as we got to see our boss here,
Pourvu qu'on puisse voir notre patron ici,
the trip wasn't wasted.
Le voyage n'a pas été inutile.
-That's right. -Yeah!
-C'est exact. -Ouais !
Today, let's have
Aujourd'hui, prenons
a good drink together,
un bon verre ensemble,
get some sleep,
Dors un peu,
and everything will be fine when we wake up.
Et tout ira bien à notre réveil.
-Yes, absolutely. -Yeah.
-Oui, absolument. -Ouais.
Let's go.
Allons-y.
-Come on, let's drink. -Let's go.
-Allez, on boit un verre. -Allons-y.
-Let's go drink.
-Allons boire un verre.
Boss.
Chef.
When you left the fortress back then,
Quand vous avez quitté la forteresse à cette époque,
we all thought
nous pensions tous
you'd be back soon.
Tu seras bientôt de retour.
We've all missed you.
Tu nous as manqué à tous.
I also...
Moi aussi...
Why don't...
Pourquoi ne pas...
you all come back with me
Vous revenez tous avec moi
to the Central Plains Sword Alliance?
à l'Alliance des Épées des Plaines Centrales ?
That would be wonderful.
Ce serait merveilleux.
But...
Mais...
We're all bandits who rule the mountain.
Nous sommes tous des bandits qui règnent sur la montagne.
Will the alliance accept us?
L'alliance nous acceptera-t-elle ?
We are...
Nous sommes...
chivalrous bandits
bandits chevaleresques
who rob the rich to help the poor.
qui volent les riches pour aider les pauvres.
Bandits? What's that supposed to mean?
Des bandits ? Qu'est-ce que ça veut dire ?
I'm well-connected in the Central Plains Sword Alliance.
J'ai de bons contacts au sein de l'Alliance des Épées des Plaines Centrales.
My reputation is formidable.
Ma réputation est formidable.
They'll definitely accept you.
Ils vous accepteront sans aucun doute.
Boss is so impressive.
Le patron est vraiment impressionnant.
Let's go.
Allons-y.
Boss.
Chef.
That runaway fiancée of yours...
Ta fiancée qui s'est enfuie...
did you find her?
L'avez-vous retrouvée ?
Chi Yun!
Chi Yun !
Boss?
Chef?
If you can't remember, don't force yourself.
Si vous ne vous en souvenez pas, ne vous forcez pas.
What exactly did I forget?
Qu'est-ce que j'ai oublié exactement ?
Boss, it's me, Datou!
Patron, c'est moi, Datou !
Boss, are you alright?
Patron, ça va ?
Don't you even recognize me?
Tu ne me reconnais même pas ?
Wake up!
Réveillez-vous!
He's been poisoned by the Blood Ghost Pill.
Il a été empoisonné par la pilule du fantôme de sang.
He can't recognize any of you now.
Il ne peut plus vous reconnaître.
Who are you?
Qui es-tu?
What did you just feed me?
Qu'est-ce que tu viens de me donner à manger ?
Mr. Tang sent me
M. Tang m'a envoyé
to take you back.
pour vous ramener.
Come with me.
Viens avec moi.
Foxy Tang?
Foxy Tang ?
How come I didn't know
Comment se fait-il que je ne le savais pas ?
he had a woman by his side?
Il avait une femme à ses côtés ?
He figured out so quickly
Il a compris si vite
the letter was forged?
La lettre était un faux ?
Why do you wear a mask?
Pourquoi portez-vous un masque ?
Why do you have so many questions?
Pourquoi posez-vous autant de questions ?
What's your surname then?
Quel est votre nom de famille alors ?
My surname is Bai.
Mon nom de famille est Bai.
-Let's go. -Go.
-Allons-y. -Allez-y.
This road is the only way
Cette route est la seule voie
to Huoyun Fortress.
vers la forteresse de Huoyun.
Following this path,
En suivant ce chemin,
I should be able to catch up with Chi Yun.
Je devrais pouvoir rattraper Chi Yun.
White Stone Formation?
Formation de pierre blanche ?
It's Bai Suche.
C'est Bai Suche.
She has found Chi Yun.
Elle a retrouvé Chi Yun.
It's getting dark.
Il commence à faire sombre.
Even if we're in a hurry, we should fill our stomachs first, right?
Même si nous sommes pressés, nous devrions d'abord nous remplir l'estomac, n'est-ce pas ?
Boss,
Chef,
look over there.
Regarde là-bas.
Isn't that an inn?
N'est-ce pas une auberge ?
[Baiwei Inn]
[Auberge Baiwei]
Guys, guys.
Les gars, les gars.
I don't even know if the Mind-Clearing Pill will last
Je ne sais même pas si la pilule éclaircissante aura un effet durable.
until he returns to the Sword Alliance.
jusqu'à son retour à l'Alliance de l'Épée.
And now they've detoured for a meal.
Et maintenant, ils ont fait un détour pour déjeuner.
I must quickly
Je dois vite
get them back
Récupérez-les
on the original path
sur le chemin d'origine
to avoid missing Mr. Tang.
pour ne pas rater M. Tang.
This wine is excellent.
Ce vin est excellent.
He's even drinking now?
Il boit même maintenant ?
The wine is so good.
Le vin est excellent.
I saved it especially for you, Boss!
Je l'ai gardé spécialement pour vous, patron !
Good wine! Cheers!
Bon vin ! Santé !
We need to get back on the road soon.
Il faut qu'on reprenne la route bientôt.
You can't drink.
Tu ne peux pas boire.
Why can't we drink?
Pourquoi ne pouvons-nous pas boire ?
We brothers haven't seen each other
Nous, les frères, ne nous sommes pas vus.
for so many years.
pendant tant d'années.
Today, we must have a proper drink.
Aujourd'hui, il nous faut absolument un verre.
Even if the gods themselves came down,
Même si les dieux eux-mêmes descendaient sur terre,
we'd still be drinking!
On serait encore en train de boire !
-That's right! -Yeah!
-C'est exact ! -Ouais !
Bottoms up!
Cul sec !
Waiter!
Serveur!
Boss, you want to switch
Patron, vous voulez changer
to a bigger bowl?
dans un bol plus grand ?
Sir!
Monsieur!
What can I get you?
Que puis-je vous offrir ?
Bring me a pot of tea.
Apportez-moi une théière.
You guys drink.
Vous buvez, les gars.
Right away.
Tout de suite.
Why do you want tea, Boss?
Pourquoi voulez-vous du thé, patron ?
Yeah, Boss.
Oui, patron.
Did I hear that right?
Ai-je bien entendu ?
You want tea?
Tu veux du thé ?
Tea? Really?
Du thé ? Vraiment ?
Enough.
Assez.
You don't understand.
Vous ne comprenez pas.
I drank adulterated wine twice in a row.
J'ai bu du vin frelaté deux fois de suite.
After drinking, my head was spinning,
Après avoir bu, j'avais la tête qui tournait.
and I couldn't remember anything.
et je ne me souvenais de rien.
It's better to drink less.
Il vaut mieux boire moins.
Waiter, hurry up with our dishes!
Garçon, dépêchez-vous avec nos plats !
You can't get drunk.
Tu ne peux pas t'enivrer.
We need to head to
Nous devons nous rendre à
the Central Plains Sword Alliance soon.
L'Alliance des Épées des Plaines Centrales bientôt.
We'll leave in two hours.
Nous partirons dans deux heures.
You all heard that, eh?
Vous avez tous entendu ça, hein ?
Drink less.
Buvez moins.
Come on, customers, this way.
Allez, clients, par ici.
-Come on, let's drink. -Come on.
-Allez, on boit un verre. -Allez.
Boss.
Chef.
Does that girl
Est-ce que cette fille
have something on you?
Tu as quelque chose sur toi ?
How much money do you owe her?
Combien d'argent lui dois-tu ?
We can all chip in and help you pay it off.
Nous pouvons tous contribuer et vous aider à rembourser.
-That's right, Boss. -Yeah.
-C'est exact, patron. -Ouais.
-We can help out.
-Oui. -Nous pouvons vous aider.
Stop talking nonsense. You don't understand.
Arrête de dire des bêtises. Tu ne comprends pas.
She cares about me.
Elle tient à moi.
That's why she's so controlling.
C'est pour ça qu'elle est si autoritaire.
I don't know why.
Je ne sais pas pourquoi.
But when she scolds me...
Mais quand elle me gronde...
Please, go upstairs.
Veuillez monter à l'étage.
I actually kind of like it.
En fait, j'aime bien.
Boss?
Chef?
You're not falling for her
Tu ne vas pas tomber amoureux d'elle
just because of her looks, are you?
C'est uniquement à cause de son physique, c'est ça ?
Falling for her looks?
Vous êtes sous le charme de son physique ?
Then we'd have to see what she looks like first.
Il faudrait donc d'abord voir à quoi elle ressemble.
We haven't even seen her face.
Nous n'avons même pas vu son visage.
She's always wearing a veil
Elle porte toujours un voile
and never shows her face.
et ne montre jamais son visage.
That can't be right, man.
Ça ne peut pas être vrai, mec.
-Yeah, exactly. -Yeah.
-Oui, exactement. -Oui.
I get it now.
Je comprends maintenant.
She must be incredibly ugly,
Elle doit être incroyablement laide,
and that's why she doesn't show her face.
Et c'est pourquoi elle ne montre pas son visage.
Maybe
Peut être
her face is covered in pockmarks,
Son visage est couvert de cicatrices d'acné,
with a crooked mouth and squinting eyes.
avec une bouche tordue et des yeux plissés.
Right?
Droite?
-Yes, exactly. -Right.
-Oui, exactement. -Exact.
Am I right?
Ai-je raison ?
-That's right. -Yeah.
-C'est exact. -Ouais.
A bunch of scoundrels.
Une bande de scélérats.
But come to think of it,
Mais à bien y réfléchir,
I don't think
Je ne pense pas
she was being harsh with me.
Elle était dure avec moi.
She actually likes me.
En fait, elle m'aime bien.
What do you mean?
Que veux-tu dire?
I'm serious.
Je suis sérieux.
When I see her, she feels
Quand je la vois, elle ressent
very familiar.
Très familier.
When she's harsh with me,
Quand elle est dure avec moi,
it feels like
on a l'impression que
my long-awaited wish
mon souhait tant attendu
has finally come true.
C'est enfin devenu réalité.
Take care, sir.
Prenez soin de vous, monsieur.
There's a feeling of satisfaction.
On éprouve un sentiment de satisfaction.
Although I don't know
Bien que je ne sache pas
why.
pourquoi.
Boss, your tolerance for alcohol has gotten worse.
Patron, votre tolérance à l'alcool a augmenté.
You're talking nonsense after just one bowl.
Tu dis n'importe quoi après avoir mangé un seul bol.
Please, come in.
Entrez, je vous prie.
Come on, let's drink.
Allez, on boit un verre.
Pour it up. Drink to our heart's content.
Servez-vous un verre. Buvez à votre guise.
Miss,
Manquer,
those guests
ces invités
have already gone upstairs to sleep.
sont déjà montés dormir.
Maybe you should just let them sleep.
Peut-être devriez-vous simplement les laisser dormir.
You can continue your journey early tomorrow morning.
Vous pourrez reprendre votre voyage tôt demain matin.
A few hours won't make much difference, right?
Quelques heures ne changeront pas grand-chose, n'est-ce pas ?
I've already called them.
Je les ai déjà appelés.
They should be down soon.
Ils devraient bientôt être hors service.
I...
JE...
If you have something to say, just say it.
Si vous avez quelque chose à dire, dites-le.
Did you...
As-tu...
hear all that stuff
entendre tout ça
I said earlier?
J'ai dit plus tôt ?
You said that on purpose for me to hear?
Vous avez dit ça exprès pour que je l'entende ?
I swear to heaven!
Je le jure devant le ciel !
All that nonsense about
Toutes ces bêtises à propos de
"crooked mouth, squinty eyes, and pockmarked face"—
«Bouche tordue, yeux plissés et visage marqué par la variole»—
I didn't say any of that.
Je n'ai rien dit de tout cela.
They said it.
Ils l'ont dit.
They were all talking nonsense.
Ils disaient tous n'importe quoi.
They're used to running their mouths.
Ils ont l'habitude de parler pour ne rien dire.
Please don't take it to heart, miss.
Ne le prenez pas mal, mademoiselle.
I don't mind.
Cela ne me dérange pas.
Miss Bai,
Mademoiselle Bai,
do you wear that veil...
Tu portes ce voile...
because of your appearance?
à cause de votre apparence ?
It's okay.
C'est bon.
After I was poisoned,
Après avoir été empoisonné,
people called me a monster too.
On m'a aussi traité de monstre.
When the poison flares up,
Lorsque le poison s'enflamme,
I look very strange as well.
J'ai aussi une allure très étrange.
People on the street even call me a demon.
Dans la rue, certains m'appellent même un démon.
It's just the outer shell. Don't let it bother you.
Ce n'est que l'enveloppe extérieure. Ne vous en faites pas.
Besides...
En plus...
I find it strange.
Je trouve ça étrange.
I don't know why I became so attached
Je ne sais pas pourquoi je me suis autant attachée.
to you the first time we met.
à toi, la première fois que nous nous sommes rencontrés.
To be honest, when I first saw you,
Pour être honnête, quand je t'ai vu pour la première fois,
my mind was filled
Mon esprit était rempli
with all kinds
avec toutes sortes
of strange thoughts.
de pensées étranges.
Like "I would rather die
Comme « je préférerais mourir »
than let anything happen to you,"
plutôt que de laisser quoi que ce soit vous arriver,
and even wanting to leave you a dowry.
et même vouloir vous laisser une dot.
Isn't that ridiculous?
N'est-ce pas ridicule ?
Probably just hallucinations from the poison.
Probablement des hallucinations dues au poison.
Don't you think...
Tu ne penses pas...
Why are you crying?
Pourquoi pleures-tu ?
Did I say something wrong?
Ai-je dit quelque chose de mal ?
What if all of that isn't a hallucination?
Et si tout cela n'était pas une hallucination ?
What if you became
Et si vous deveniez
like this because of me?
comme ça à cause de moi ?
That can't be it, right?
Ce n'est pas possible, n'est-ce pas ?
Foxy Tang said I was
Foxy Tang a dit que j'étais
poisoned by someone.
empoisonné par quelqu'un.
I was already poisoned
J'étais déjà empoisonné
before I met you.
avant de te rencontrer.
Could it be that you...
Se pourrait-il que vous...
knew me before?
Vous me connaissiez déjà ?
Foxy Tang won't tell me
Foxy Tang ne veut pas me le dire
how I ended up poisoned.
Comment j'ai fini par être empoisonné.
If you know,
Si vous savez,
could you tell me?
Pourriez-vous me le dire ?
Can't let Chi Yun
Impossible de laisser Chi Yun
remember West Wind Garden again.
Souvenez-vous de West Wind Garden.
When we get back to the Sword Alliance,
Lorsque nous reviendrons à l'Alliance de l'Épée,
I'll tell you then.
Je vous le dirai alors.
I'll go urge them to hurry.
Je vais aller les presser de se dépêcher.
Why such a rush to get to the Sword Alliance?
Pourquoi une telle précipitation pour rejoindre l'Alliance de l'Épée ?
In the middle of the night, we have to push on
Au milieu de la nuit, nous devons continuer.
instead of sleeping.
au lieu de dormir.
Just get on the road when you're told.
Prenez la route quand on vous le dira.
Right,
Droite,
Miss Bai?
Mademoiselle Bai ?
Boss, why do you trust her so much?
Patron, pourquoi lui faites-vous autant confiance ?
I feel like
J'ai l'impression que
Miss Bai is deliberately taking us on a detour.
Mademoiselle Bai nous fait délibérément faire un détour.
The fastest route
L'itinéraire le plus rapide
to the Sword Alliance goes past West Wind Garden,
L'Alliance de l'Épée passe devant le Jardin du Vent d'Ouest,
but she's leading us around through the Western Ridge.
mais elle nous fait faire le tour de la crête ouest.
West Wind Garden?
Jardin du Vent de l'Ouest ?
Oh no!
Oh non!
Boss?
Chef?
What are you trying to do
Qu'essayez-vous de faire ?
to our boss, you woman?
à notre patron, vous êtes une femme ?
Move aside!
Écartez-vous !
If we don't knock him out now...
Si on ne le met pas KO maintenant...
Are you alright, Boss?
Ça va, patron ?
No one will be able to stop him once he loses control!
Personne ne pourra l'arrêter une fois qu'il aura perdu le contrôle !
I suspected
Je soupçonnais
something was wrong with you all along.
Il y avait quelque chose qui clochait chez toi depuis le début.
Boss likes you,
Votre patron vous apprécie.
so I kept quiet.
Alors je me suis tu.
You've been leaving marks along the road,
Vous avez laissé des traces sur la route,
exposing our location the whole way.
révélant ainsi notre position tout au long du trajet.
However,
Cependant,
don't expect
ne vous attendez pas à
your accomplices to find us.
vos complices pour nous trouver.
I've changed all the marks you made
J'ai effacé toutes les marques que tu as faites.
to point in the opposite direction.
pointer dans la direction opposée.
You changed all my markers?
Tu as changé tous mes marqueurs ?
Move aside now.
Écartez-vous maintenant.
He's about to lose control!
Il est sur le point de perdre le contrôle !
Who are you trying to fool?
Qui essayez-vous de tromper ?
We're not as
Nous ne sommes pas aussi
gullible as Boss.
aussi naïf que le patron.
This direction is wrong.
Cette direction est incorrecte.
Did someone tamper with the marks?
Quelqu'un a-t-il falsifié les marques ?
Chi Yun has been missing for so long.
Chi Yun est porté disparu depuis si longtemps.
I can't keep going in circles anymore.
Je ne peux plus tourner en rond.
Soul-Seeking.
À la recherche de son âme.
Master Shao?
Maître Shao ?
Why is Master Shao here?
Pourquoi Maître Shao est-il ici ?
Chi Yun.
Chi Yun.
Boss...
Chef...
why?
pourquoi ?
Chi Yun!
Chi Yun !
Chi Yun, wake up!
Chi Yun, réveille-toi !
Rebirth Scroll—
Parchemin de renaissance —
Truth.
Vérité.
Release.
Libérer.
Chi Yun.
Chi Yun.
Wake up.
Réveillez-vous.
Boss, why...
Patron, pourquoi...
Kill me...
Tue-moi...
Using your blood to suppress the poison
Utiliser son sang pour neutraliser le poison
can indeed slow
peut effectivement ralentir
its onset.
son apparition.
But if he loses control again,
Mais s'il perd à nouveau le contrôle,
it will trigger a violent backlash.
Cela déclenchera une violente réaction.
At best, he'll die like the others,
Au mieux, il mourra comme les autres.
his body exploding.
son corps explosant.
At worst, he'll become like Yu Qifeng—
Au pire, il deviendra comme Yu Qifeng…
who knows what kind of monster he'll turn into.
Qui sait quel genre de monstre il deviendra ?
If that day ever comes...
Si ce jour arrive un jour...
I advise you to be merciful
Je vous conseille d'être miséricordieux.
and end his suffering quickly.
et mettre fin rapidement à ses souffrances.
You just took that old fool Yu's strike head-on,
Tu as encaissé de plein fouet l'attaque de ce vieux fou de Yu,
and now you want to drink?
Et maintenant, tu as envie de boire ?
Your stomachache...
Votre mal de ventre...
I'm telling you, it's been a year,
Je vous le dis, ça fait un an,
and it hasn't gotten any better.
Et la situation ne s'est pas améliorée.
Anyway,
De toute façon,
you can't be that Yique Yinyang
Tu ne peux pas être ce Yique Yinyang
who brought disaster to the country.
qui a plongé le pays dans le désastre.
Besides,
En plus,
those golden eyes and that forehead mark of yours
tes yeux dorés et cette marque sur ton front
♪ I cross the Yan River in the wasteland ♪
♪ Je traverse la rivière Yan dans le désert ♪
are actually kind of cool.
sont plutôt sympas, en fait.
♪ Singing a long, unfinished song ♪
♪ Chanter une longue chanson inachevée ♪
♪ The full moon and a few shining stars ♪
♪ La pleine lune et quelques étoiles brillantes ♪
Anyone there?
Il y a quelqu'un ?
♪ Look down on my dream ♪
♪ Contemplez mon rêve ♪
Foxy Tang...
Foxy Tang...
♪ The breeze blows through the pleats ♪
♪ La brise souffle à travers les plis ♪
You're here.
Vous êtes ici.
I've been waiting for you for so long.
Je t'attends depuis si longtemps.
I waited from day...
J'ai attendu depuis le jour...
♪ Water polishes the old ruts ♪
♪ L'eau polit les vieilles ornières ♪
until night.
jusqu'à la nuit.
And I waited from night until day again.
Et j'ai attendu de la nuit jusqu'au jour.
But you never came.
Mais tu n'es jamais venu.
I'm sorry.
Je suis désolé.
I came too late.
Je suis arrivé trop tard.
In this lifetime...
Dans cette vie...
I actually got to hear you apologize.
J'ai effectivement entendu vos excuses.
But...
Mais...
I won't forgive you.
Je ne te pardonnerai pas.
Save it for our next life...
Gardons-le pour notre prochaine vie...
when you can say it again.
quand vous pouvez le répéter.
♪ The breeze blows through the pleats ♪
♪ La brise souffle à travers les plis ♪
I'm sorry.
Je suis désolé.
♪ Water polishes the old ruts ♪
♪ L'eau polit les vieilles ornières ♪
Chi Yun...
Chi Yun...
♪ Destiny entwining my fleeting life, I can't fight ♪
♪ Le destin enlace ma vie éphémère, je ne peux lutter ♪
Say something.
Dire quelque chose.
Say something to me, please.
Dites-moi quelque chose, s'il vous plaît.
Chi Yun!
Chi Yun !
♪ Trapped in the loop of loneliness ♪
♪ Pris au piège de la solitude ♪
Say something.
Dire quelque chose.
What were you about to tell me?
Qu'alliez-vous me dire ?
Say it!
Dis-le !
Don't you want to marry me?
Tu ne veux pas m'épouser ?
I'll marry you.
Je t'épouserai.
Please say something!
Dites quelque chose, s'il vous plaît !
Say something...
Dire quelque chose...
Chi Yun!
Chi Yun !
♪ Trapped in the loop of loneliness ♪
♪ Pris au piège de la solitude ♪
I'm sorry.
Je suis désolé.
Master Shao...
Maître Shao...
Are you waiting for Shao Yanping?
Attendez-vous Shao Yanping ?
Too bad. He won't be coming.
Dommage. Il ne viendra pas.
Yan used himself to test the medicine.
Yan s'est servi de lui-même pour tester le médicament.
His body is already very weak.
Son corps est déjà très faible.
We are no match for Xifang Tao.
Nous ne faisons pas le poids face à Xifang Tao.
If Yan can escape,
Si Yan parvient à s'échapper,
Tang Lici will be able to protect him.
Tang Lici pourra le protéger.
Yan, run!
Yan, cours !
Sacrificing yourself just to buy Liu Yan a chance to flee?
Se sacrifier juste pour donner à Liu Yan une chance de s'enfuir ?
I told you before,
Je vous l'ai déjà dit,
you should find another man.
Tu devrais trouver un autre homme.
Silly girl,
Petite sotte,
treating men like this
traiter les hommes comme ça
only makes them care less about you.
Cela ne fait que les dissuader de s'intéresser à vous.
Be a smart girl
Sois une fille intelligente
in your next life.
dans ta prochaine vie.
Heaven-Changing Scripture—
Les Écritures qui changent le ciel —
Silver River Falls from the Ninth Heaven.
Les chutes de Silver River du Neuvième Ciel.
Stop.
Arrêt.
Yan.
Oui.
Let Xiaohong go.
Laissez partir Xiaohong.
It's been a long time,
Ça fait longtemps,
Master Liu.
Maître Liu.
Who would have thought
Qui l'eût cru ?
that the once noble and revered Master Liu
que le maître Liu, jadis noble et vénéré,
would live in a place like this?
Est-ce que vous vivriez dans un endroit comme celui-ci ?
This place is far too crude,
Cet endroit est beaucoup trop rudimentaire,
hardly suitable for developing the antidote.
Difficilement adapté au développement de l'antidote.
Come back to the Sword Alliance with me.
Reviens avec moi à l'Alliance des Épées.
Do you want to come with me on your own,
Veux-tu venir avec moi seul(e) ?
or shall I take you by force?
Ou dois-je vous prendre par la force ?
Do you choose to leave on your own,
Choisissez-vous de partir de votre propre initiative ?
or do you choose to die here?
Ou choisissez-vous de mourir ici ?
Is this your last resort
Est-ce votre dernier recours ?
to save your life?
pour vous sauver la vie ?
At worst,
Au pire,
we'll die together.
Nous mourrons ensemble.
I've changed my mind.
J'ai changé d'avis.
Let Xiaohong go.
Laissez partir Xiaohong.
Yan.
Oui.
Liu Yan.
Liu Yan.
Did you become soft-hearted
Êtes-vous devenu plus sensible ?
after experiencing great calamity,
après avoir subi une grande calamité,
or have you
ou avez-vous
always been this way?
Ça a toujours été comme ça ?